Who will save the day? The ice guy? The nice guy? The snow man? Or no man?
Frozen is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Jennifer Lee.
Young princess Anna of Arendelle dreams about finding
true love at her sister Elsa’s coronation.
Fate takes her on a dangerous journey in an attempt to end the
eternal winter that has fallen over the kingdom.
She's accompanied by ice delivery man Kristoff, his
reindeer Sven, and snowman Olaf.
On an adventure where she will find out what friendship,
courage, family, and true love really means.
Elsa (voice), played by Idina Menzel.
Anna (voice), played by Kristen Bell.
Kristoff (voice), played by Jonathan Groff.
Olaf (voice), played by Josh Gad.
Young Anna (voice), played by Livvy Stubenrauch.
Hans (voice), played by Santino Fontana.
Frozen is a 2013 American animated musical fantasy film produced by Walt
Disney Animation Studios and released by Walt Disney Pictures.
Inspired by Hans Christian Andersen's 1844 fairy tale "The Snow Queen", it was directed by Chris Buck and Jennifer Lee and
produced by Peter Del Vecho, from a screenplay by Lee, who also conceived the film's story with Buck and Shane Morris.
The film stars the voices of Kristen Bell, Idina Menzel,
Jonathan Groff, Josh Gad, and Santino Fontana.
It follows Anna, the princess of Arendelle, who sets off on a journey with the iceman Kristoff, his reindeer Sven, and the snowman
Olaf, to find her estranged sister Elsa after she accidentally traps their kingdom in eternal winter with her icy powers.
Frozen underwent several story treatments before it was commissioned in 2011.
Christophe Beck was hired to compose the film's orchestral score, and
Robert Lopez and Kristen Anderson-Lopez wrote the songs.
After its world premiere at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on November 19,
2013, Frozen had its general theatrical release on November 27.
It was praised for its visuals, screenplay, themes, music, and voice acting, and some critics
consider it Disney's best animated film since the studio's Renaissance era.
The film grossed over $1.280 billion worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing animated film
until the remake of The Lion King overtook this position in August 2019.
It finished its theatrical run as the highest-grossing film of 2013
and the fifth-highest-grossing film of all time.
The film's songs, characters, story, and appeal to a general
audience led to it being dubbed a pop culture phenomenon.
The film's popularity spawned a franchise, which includes a short, Frozen Fever (2015), a featurette, Olaf's Frozen
Adventure (2017), and two feature-length sequels—Frozen 2 (2019) and the upcoming Frozen 3 (2027).
Among its accolades, it won Academy Awards for Best Animated Feature and Best Original Song with Let It Go, the Golden
Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film, the BAFTA Award for Best Animated Film, and two Grammy Awards.
The film explores themes of princess, magic, mistake in person, queen, cartoon.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting.